Brian Hamburg

Summary

With over a decade of experience building user interfaces for the Web and providing technical support, my focus has always been to remove friction from the user experience, with a strong appreciation for both accessibility and aesthetics.

Experience

American Red Cross / Remote

Full-stack Developer / February 2021 - Present

Maintaining and creating editable components for the enterprise content management system and associated APIs for redcross.org and redcrossblood.org as a member of a fully-remote software development team.

Key technologies include Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) running on Amazon Web Services (AWS), HTL (Sightly) templates using vanilla JS, Angular, jQuery, and Bootstrap on the front end, with Java/Sling/OSGi on the back end, automated testing with Cypress, JUnit, and Jasmine, and CI/CD via Bitbucket and Jenkins.

Thomas Jefferson University and Jefferson Health / Philadelphia, PA

Web Developer / July 2015 - February 2021

As a member of Jefferson's IS&T department, created and maintained editable web templates and components for public-facing websites built within AEM with HTL (Sightly), server-side JavaScript, and Java. Often contributed to the development of other front-end web applications as needed, utilizing vanilla JS and React, Sass/CSS, and HTML.

Front-End Web Developer / September 2012 – July 2015

As a member of Jefferson's marketing team, created landing pages, microsites, WordPress themes, banner ads, and email campaigns for clinical and university clients. Updated existing Sitecore templates for the main hospital website. Redesigned the hospital "JEFF NOW" appointment request form with a responsive layout, enhancing usability and decreasing the abandonment rate. Administered and trained users in WordPress, SurveyGizmo, and MailChimp.

Law School Admission Council / Newtown, PA

Web Services Specialist / September 2008 – September 2012

Created new and updated existing web pages for LSAC.org to adhere to accessibility guidelines and strict W3C standards. Converted the intranet portal from a static web site to a Microsoft SharePoint site with custom ASP.NET master pages, page layouts, and style sheets. Administered WebTrends and Google Analytics on LSAC.org and the intranet portal. Created and maintained online surveys in SurveyGizmo with Salesforce integration.

Information Systems Specialist / September 2006 – September 2008

Provided technical support to internal employees and external customers, diagnosing and documenting technical issues pertaining to the company's web site, in-house software, and licensed software. Trained and assisted co-workers to support Macintosh users. Provided quality assurance testing for online law school applications and contributed to documentation for law school application creation and QA processes.

Education

Master's Certificate in Application Development

Obtained in 2013 while pursuing Master of Science degree in Computer Science / La Salle University

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration / La Salle University / Graduated 2011, Magna Cum Laude

Associate of Arts in Busines Administration / Bucks County Community College / Graduated 2010

Associate of Arts in Graphic Design / CHI Institute / Graduated 2006